mattdavella.com 2019-03-24

# Matt D'Avella

### **Privacy Policy**

We at Catalyst Films LLC (“we”, “our”, “us”) share this Privacy Policy with you as a user or viewer of mattdavella.com. We want you to know how we use the information you share with us.

This Privacy Policy has been compiled to inform you how your ‘Personally Identifiable Information’ (PII) is used online by Catalyst Films LLC PII is information that can be used (on its own or which other information) to identify, contact, or locate an individual or identify an individual in context. We process PII as a Data Controller, as defined by the General Data Protection Regulation.

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy without notice. By using or viewing Catalyst Films LLC, you agree to it, regardless of whether or not you’ve read it.

### California Online Privacy Protection Act (CalOPPA)

We present this Privacy Policy in compliance with CalOPPA state law which requires commercial websites to post a privacy policy to collect PII from California consumers.

See more at: <http://consumercal.org/california-online-privacy-protection-act-caloppa/#sthash.0FdRbT51.dpuf>

In accordance with CalOPPA, we agree to the following:

  * Users can visit our site anonymously.

  * This Privacy Policy is linked on our homepage or the first significant page after entering Catalyst Films LLC

  * Our Privacy Policy link includes the word ‘Privacy’ and can easily be found on the page specified above.

### Personal Identifiable Information

What personal information do we collect?

When ordering or signing up on our site, you may be asked to enter information to help us personalize your online experience with Catalyst Films LLC. You may be asked to enter the following: name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information, or other details.

When do we collect information?

We collect information from you when you place an order, subscribe to a newsletter, navigate the website, or enter information on our site via survey or marketing communication.

You may decline to provide certain information to us, in which case we may not be able to provide you access to certain features and functionalities of the site.

How do we use your information?

We may use the information we collect in the following ways:

Name: To address you appropriately and verify your identity

Email Address: To serve as a point of contact, to share information and materials with you

Mailing Address: To ship your purchased orders

Phone Number: To aid in efficient order deliveries

Credit Card Information: To process your orders securely

How do we protect your information?

We use regular Malware Scanning to detect security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

We use the following third-party data processors to collect and store information: ConvertKit, WooCommerce, LeadPages.

Your personal information is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible to a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems. These persons are required by contract to keep the information confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit information you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

All transactions are processed through a gateway provider and are not stored or processed on our servers.

### General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

In compliance with the GDPR, you have the right to access information we have about you by emailing us at hello@mattdavella.com with “Privacy Policy” in the subject line. We must be able to verify your identity before providing you with an electronic copy of your information.

We will comply with any request to correct, delete, or withdraw consent to our use of your information.

If you feel the rights granted to you have been violated, you agree to contact Catalyst Films LLC. as soon as possible at hello@mattdavella.com with “Privacy Policy” in the subject line.

See more here: [https://www.eugdpr.org](https://www.eugdpr.org/)

### Retention

We retain your information for as long as required to respond to and resolve inquiries and to process and share relevant information with you about ordered products. For mailing list subscriptions, we retain your information for as long as you remain subscribed (i.e. you do not unsubscribe).

### Tracking

‘Cookies’

We use cookies to help us understand your preferences in order to offer you an efficient and personalized experience on our website.

You can choose to have your computer notify you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies in your browser settings. Look at your individual browser’s Help Menu to learn the correct way to modify your cookies.If you turn cookies off, some of the features that make your site experience more efficient and personalized may not function properly.

Using Google Analytics, as a third-party vendor, we collect the following data:

  * Demographics and Interests

All of our activity complies with Google Analytics Terms of Service. More information on how Google uses data can be found here: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/

Do Not Track signals

We honor Do Not Track (DNT) signals and do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when a DNT browser mechanism is in place.

Third-party disclosure

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your PII unless we provide users with advance notice. This does not include website hosting partners and other parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or serving our users, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release information when its release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

Non-personally identifiable information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

Google

Google’s advertising requirements can be summed up by Google’s Advertising Principles: https://support.google.com/adwordspolicy/answer/1316548?hl=en

Google, as a third-party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our site. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to our users based on previous visits to our site and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt-out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google Ad and Content Network privacy policy.

We have implemented collection of the follow data:

  * Demographics and Interests

We, along with third-party vendors such as Google, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) or other third-party identifiers together to compile data regarding user interactions with ad impressions and other ad service functions as they relate to our website.

### Opting out:

You can set preferences for how Google advertises to you using the Google Ad Settings page. Alternatively, you can opt out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative Opt Out page or by using the Google Analytics Opt Out Browser add on.

### Children Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

We comply with COPPA and do not knowingly market to or allow third-parties to collect PII from children under the age of 13. We require the consent of a parent or guardian to collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

### Fair Information Practices

In compliance with Fair Information Practices we will take the following responsive action, should a data breach occur:

  * We will notify you via email within 7 business days.

We agree to the Individual Redress Principle which requires that individuals have the right to legally pursue enforceable rights against data collectors and processors who fail to adhere to the law.

### Unsubscribe/Opt-out

You reserve the right to opt-out of receiving future emails. If you wish to do so: Follow the instructions located at the bottom of each email. We will remove you from all correspondence.

### CAN-SPAM Act

The CAN-SPAM Act sets rules for commercial email, establishes requirements for commercial messages, gives recipients the right to unsubscribe from emails, and indicates the penalties for violations.

We collect your email address in order to:

  * Send information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

  * Process orders and to send information and updates pertaining to orders.

  * Send you additional information related to your product and/or service.

  * Market to our mailing list or continue to send emails to our clients after an original transaction has occurred.

In accordance with CAN-SPAM, we agree to the following:

  * Not use false or misleading subjects or email addresses.

  * Identify the message as an advertisement in a reasonable way.

  * Include the physical address of our business or site headquarters.

  * Monitor third-party email marketing services for compliance, if one is used.

  * Allow users to unsubscribe by using the link at the bottom of each email.

### Contacting Us

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy or your PII rights, you may contact us at hello@mattdavella.com with “Privacy Policy” in the subject line.

 _Updated – January 2019_
